wbez.org 2018-04-17

# Privacy Policy | Chicago Public Media

## CHICAGO PUBLIC MEDIA PRIVACY POLICY

EFFECTIVE DATE: September 25, 2014

Your privacy is important to us. This Privacy Policy explains what type of information is collected from you when you visit our sites located at chicagopublicmedia.org, wbez.org, vocalo.org, soundopinions.org and thisamericanlife.org (collectively, the “Sites”) and how that information may be used.

By using the Sites, you signify your agreement to the terms and conditions of our Privacy Policy and Terms of Use. If you do not agree to these terms and conditions, please do not use the Sites. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please exit the Sites and do not use the Sites. We reserve the right, at our discretion, to modify, add or delete portions of these terms at any time by posting an updated Privacy Policy on the Sites. Please check this Privacy Policy frequently for updates. Any modifications, additions or deletions to this Privacy Policy shall be effective immediately upon posting. Your continued use of the Sites following the posting of an updated Privacy Policy will mean that you agree to such changes.

 **INFORMATION AUTOMATICALLY GATHERED WHEN YOU VISIT A SITE**

Our web servers automatically creates log files for each visitor who accesses our Sites. These “access logs” allow us to enhance the Sites for all visitors. The access logs do not record a visitor’s name, address, phone number, credit card numbers, or any other personally identifying information. Rather, these log files may contain some or all of the following information: the date of the visit; the time and length of the visit; the path taken through the Sites; the browser being used; a list of files downloaded or viewed; the amount of time spent listening to audio files; the Internet Protocol Address (IP Address), as may be assigned by your Internet Service Provider, of the machine accessing our Sites; and any errors encountered.

We use this information to aid the technical administration of the Sites and to better understand how the Sites are functioning for users and for marketing purposes. This information may be correlated with your profile, if you have provided this data either through registration or a purchase via the Sites. This information may also be used in aggregate form by us and/or authorized third parties.

We may track your visit to sections of our Sites in order for some site features to function properly for you. In some instances, “cookies” or a similar technology may be used to update your registration records with session information. If you do not wish to accept a cookie from our servers, you can adjust the settings on your browser accordingly. Refusing to accept cookies from our server may result in some limits on the benefits that we can provide to you via the Sites.

Our sites utilize remarketing services through Google Adwords and other vendors to help us better serve our audience. Based on information that we automatically collect and information that you provide to us, we may display targeted banner ads tailored to you based on your previous interactions with our sites. Google may also display targeted ads tailor made for you on outside sites based on your previous interactions with our sites. We may also send you an email encouraging you to complete a previously abandoned donation form, or to return to a previously visited website offering events or content, both audio and digital. To opt-out of certain third party tracking, including Google, please [click here](http://optout.aboutads.info/).

 **PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We do not collect personally-identifying information from the Sites unless you choose to provide that information to us.

We may ask you to provide certain personal information when you: (a) register for a contest; (b) sign up for an email list; (c) request information; (d) purchase products or services; (e) submit Content that may be used on the Sites; (f) participate in a forum, bulletin board or chat; (g) become a member; (e) make a financial contribution; (f) register for an account; or (g) fill out a survey. Required personal information will be identified as such at the time the personal information is requested.

This information may be used to: (a) verify your identity; (b) manage a contest; (c) gather your editorial comments and feedback; (d) contact you for additional information; (e) send you an email newsletter; (f) ensure our sites are working at maximum performance and (g) fulfill your order or request. We may also use this information for marketing and promotional purposes. By providing this information, you may receive an occasional email or letter from us. You will be given the option to opt-out of any such listing or have your information removed from a list as set forth in this Privacy Policy. We do not share, trade or sell a donor's personally identifiable information with anyone except third parties who are performing work on our behalf pursuant to a contract.  We do not send donor mailings on behalf of other organizations.

 **SMS TEXT MESSAGING PROMOTIONS**

We occasionally use SMS text messaging promotions. By texting to a Chicago Public Media short code or by submitting your phone number in a Chicago Public Media web form, you consent to receive one or more automated texts at the phone number from which you texted or at the phone number you entered in the form. Some of these automated texts may market goods or services to you.

Unless otherwise indicated in the Chicago Public Media advertisement, there are no charges from Chicago Public Media with respect to SMS text messages, provided that your carrier’s message & data rates may apply. No purchase is necessary in order to receive texts, nor is consent to any text subscription required to purchase goods or services.

Messages for alert subscriptions will recur. The frequency of messages will vary. For additional help, text HELP in reply to a text message you receive. To cancel your SMS subscriptions, text STOP in reply to a text message you receive. You may receive a subsequent message confirming your opt-out request. SMS messages may be available to subscribers of your carrier. Please contact your carrier for availability details.

You must be 13 years of age or older to use WBEZ’s SMS services.

 **DEMOGRAPHIC AND PROFILE INFORMATION**

We occasionally conduct online surveys, sometimes in association with a contest or other offer. These surveys may ask you for demographic information such as ZIP code, age, education or income level. This information is used in an aggregate form to help us understand our audiences and improve our services. Demographic and profile information may be shared with selected third-party organizations, only on an aggregate basis, to describe the nature of our online audiences, as well as to further understand our audience’s behavior so that we may better serve them.

 **CREDIT CARD INFORMATION**

You must be 18 to engage in transactions on the Sites. When you do so, you may be asked for a credit card number. All financial transactions take place only on secure servers. Electronic communication of credit card information is sent only in a secured or encrypted format. Your credit card information is considered completely confidential. We strive to be compliant with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards.

 **CORRECTION / REMOVAL OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Please direct all requests for correction or removal of your personal information to us using the contact information below. If you want to correct your personal information on file, you may notify us at any time by writing to us via the contact information below. Notwithstanding the above, you acknowledge and understand that it may be impossible to delete personal information entirely, such as personal information existing in backups and other records. This will not remove any Content intended for public display on the Sites.

 **CHILDREN UNDER 13**

We do not seek or knowingly collect any personal information about children under 13 years of age. If we become aware that we have unknowingly collected personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will make commercially reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database.

 **THIRD PARTY WEBSITES**

The Sites may contain links to other websites. We are not responsible for third party website privacy policies, practices or content. Occasionally, you may receive cookies from third party advertisers, partners and vendors. We do not control these cookies.

 **INTERNATIONAL USER NOTICE**

For international users, please note that it may be necessary to transfer your information internationally and, in particular, your information may be transferred to and processed in the United States. For residents of the European Union: the data protection and other laws of other countries outside of the European Union may not be as comprehensive as those of the European Union. Please be assured that we take steps to ensure that your privacy is protected as described in this policy. By using the Sites, you agree to have your information used and transferred to the United States as set forth in this policy.

 **CONTACT**

By mail: Chicago Public Media, Inc., 848 East Grand Ave., Chicago, IL 60611

By e-mail: [membership@chicagopublicmedia.org](mailto:membership@chicagopublicmedia.org)
